A Guide to the Richmond Organization for Sexual Minority Youth, Records, 1990-2005
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
Richmond Organization for Sexual Minority Youth, Records, 1990-2005
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
M 369
1.5 Linear feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated on June 26, 2006 by John Dougherty, Executive Director of the organization.
Historical Information
The Richmond Organization for Sexual Minority Youth (ROSMY) was founded in 1991 by local educators, mental health practitioners, and members of the gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender community concerned about the welfare of young people struggling with identity issues. Their mission is to enhance the general well-being of sexual minority youth through support, education, advocacy and opportunities. ROSMY has grown to serve lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and questioning youth ages 14-21 through a variety of services and programs in the Metro Richmond area. ROSMY provides services such as counseling, and opportunity for discussion in a safe and supportive environment.
[Information taken from the collection including a ROSMY packet with brochures for the Second Annual ROSMY Dining for the Future, 2002]
Scope and Content
The collection consists of organizational files, which includes agendas, minutes, reports and correspondence, published newsletters, memorabilia and event posters. The bulk of the collection dates from 1990-2005. There is a significant amount of information and files on the organization's board of directors' activities, various committee programs, and published newsletters devoted to fulfilling their mission of providing support, education, advocacy and opportunities for sexual minority youth under 21 years of age.
Arrangement
The folders are arranged in four series alphabetically and chronologically. Series I: Organizational Files (1966, 1990-2006); Series II: Publications (1992-2004); Series III: Memorabilia (n.d.); and Series IV: Oversize (n.d., 1999-2003).
Contents List
- Organizational Files 1966, 1990-2006 (Box 1-5)
  - Annual Meeting - Invitation 2003 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Annual Meeting - Materials 2002 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Annual Meeting - Materials 2003 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Annual Report 1997 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Annual Report 1998 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Annual Report 2000 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Annual Report 2001 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Annual Report 2002 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Annual Report 2003 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Annual Report, Planning and Correspondence 2004, 2005 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Annual Report, Planning and Correspondence 2005 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes of Meetings 1991 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes of Meetings 1992 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Board of Directors - Budgets 1992-1995 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Board of Directors - Agendas 1993 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes of Meetings 1994 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Board of Directors - Agendas, Minutes, Reports and Records of Meetings 1997 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Board of Directors - Agendas, Minutes, Reports and Records of Meetings 1998 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Board of Directors - Rosters of Members 1998-2004 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Board of Directors - Agendas, Minutes, Reports and Records of Meetings 1999 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes of Meetings 2000 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes of Meetings 2001 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes of Meetings 2002 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes of Meetings 2003 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Board of Directors - Correspondence 2004 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes of Meetings 2004 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Board of Directors - Retreat - Planning, Correspondence and Schedule 2004-2005 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Board of Directors - Correspondence 2005 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes of Meetings 2005 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Committees Lists 1998-2004 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Committee - Auction - Planning 2000-2001 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Committee - Development - Records 1990s (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Committee - Development - Records 2000 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Committee - Development - Plans 2000-2003 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Committee - Development - Correspondence 2001 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Committee - Development - Records 2002 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Committee - Development - Plans and Records 2003 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Committee - Development - Plans 2003-2004 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Committee - Development - Potential Plans, Correspondence and Records 2004 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Committee - Development - Correspondence 2005 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Committee - Development - Miscellaneous materials undated (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Committee - Executive - Records 1999 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Committee - Finance - Records 2000-2002 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Committee - Fundraising - Planning and announcements 1993, 2006 (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Committee - Grants 2002-2003 (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Minutes 1966 (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Records 1991 (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Minutes 1992 (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Records 1993 (Box-folder 3:18)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Minutes 1994 (Box-folder 3:19)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Report 1995 (Box-folder 3:20)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Records 1996 (Box-folder 3:21)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Roster 1996-1997 (Box-folder 3:22)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Records 1997 (Box-folder 3:23)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Minutes and correspondence 1998 (Box-folder 3:24)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Records 2003 (Box-folder 3:25)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Employee Hire and Release Information 2005 (Box-folder 3:26)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Correspondence and Interview Schedule and Guide on Candidates for Executive Director Position 2006 (Box-folder 3:27)
  - Committee - Human Resources - Miscellaneous materials undated (Box-folder 3:28)
  - Committee - Marketing 2002-2003 (Box-folder 3:29)
  - Committee - Professional Services - Advisory Council Minutes 1997 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Committee - Professional Services - Agendas, Minutes, Reports, Correspondence and Notes 1998 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Committee - Professional Services - Agendas, Minutes, Records and Reports 1999 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Committee - Professional Services - Minutes 2000 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Committee - Professional Services - Agendas and Records 2001 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Committee - Professional Services - Agenda 2002 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Committee - Professional Services - Correspondence 2005 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Committee - Professional Services - Miscellaneous materials undated (Box-folder 4:8)
  - Committee - Public Education - ROSMY Speaker's Manual July 1993 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - Committee - Public Education - Records 2003-2005 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Committee - Public Education - Correspondence 2000-2004 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Committee - Public Education - Public Education Presentations 2004-2005 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Committee - Youth Advisory Council 1999 (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Open House and Annual Meeting Sign-in Sheets undated (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Organizational Materials including Certificate and Articles of Incorporation, By Laws, Personnel Policies, Programs and Committees Informations undated (Box-folder 5:2)
  - ROSMY Logos 2003, undated (Box-folder 5:3)
  - ROSMY Packets for Second Annual ROSMY Dining for the Future 2002 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - ROSMY Packets for 2005 Board Meeting 2005 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Miscellaneous materials including Donation Options, Tips, and Resource List undated (Box-folder 5:6)
- Publications 1992-2004 (Box 5)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 1992 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 1993 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 1994 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 1995 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 1996 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 1997 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 1998 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 1999 (Box-folder 5:14)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 2000 (Box-folder 5:15)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 2001 (Box-folder 5:16)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 2003 (Box-folder 5:17)
  - ROSMY Newsletter 2004 (Box-folder 5:18)
- Memorabilia undated (Box 5)
  - Event Tickets undated (Box-folder 5:19)
- Oversize Materials 1999, 2003, undated (Box 6)
  - Leadership Council Pin undated (Box 6)
  - ROSMY T-shirt undated (Box 6)
  - Event Posters 1999, 2003, undated (Box 6)